Guide to the Adelaide Taber Young papers, 1887-1911.
Young, Adelaide Taber papers, 1887-1911.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Adelaide Taber Young papers, 1887-1911.
37-5-820
Adelaide Taber Young, 1877-1964.
1.8 cubic ft.
Correspondance, photographs, scrapbooks and clippings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of Adelaide Taber Young include letters written to her mother during her studies at Cornell, largely concerning student life, sorority affairs, and social activities; student notebooks; scrapbooks of photographs, programs, clippings, and other memorabilia from Cornell and Elmira College, including items concerning her sister, Sara Louise (Elmira Class of 1904).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
After graduation from Cornell University (Class of 1899), Adelaide Young taught biology and physiology at Elmira College, Elmira, New York. She married Dr. Farnham Horatio Shaw.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers of Adelaide Taber Young include letters written to her mother during her studies at Cornell, largely concerning student life, sorority affairs, and social activities; student notebooks; scrapbooks (4 vols., 1894-1904) of photographs, programs, clippings, and other memorabilia from Cornell and Elmira College, including items concerning her sister, Sara Louise (Elmira Class of 1904); a book of American history notes (1898); 53 photographs of trees identified by their Latin names, with a letter (1901) from Professor Willard W. Rowlee of the Cornell Botany Department concerning them, and 22 pressed and mounted botanical specimens (unidentified); a letter (1901) from George Lincoln Burr; correspondence (1890-1901) with family and friends; photographs of friends and relatives from her hometown, Wellsboro, Pennsylvania, from Cornell and Ithaca, and from Elmira College.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Young, Adelaide Taber, 1877-1964.; Burr, George Lincoln, 1857-1938.; Rowlee, Willard W.; Young family.; Young, Sara Louise.; Cornell University--Students.; Elmira College--Students.
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.; Students--Recreation.; Trees.; Women college students.; Women college teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Notebooks.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- 2 scrapbooks of memorabilia ( 1901-1904 ) from Elmira College (Box 1)
- 1 undergraduate scrapbook of A.T. Young from Cornell, 1806-1899 (Box 1)
- 1 book of Cornell blue-tinted photos (Box 1)
- 1 printed book Cornell vs. Penn (1896) - official sourvenir, Thanksgiving football game, 1896 (Box 1)
- 1 American History notebook, Jan.-May 1898; apparently Miss Young's; professor unknown (Box 1)
- 1 diary-scrapbook of Miss Taber's, for a brief period in 1894 (Box 1)
- 1 folder of correspondence with friends, family, Burr and Rowlee letters, letter from Elmira College ( 1890-1901 ) (15 pieces) (Box 2)
- Several folders of memorabilia, Cornell, Elmira, and other (Box 2)
- Photos, 1887-1911 (Box 2)
- 53 identified photos of trees in Ithaca area (Box 3)
- 22 pressed and mounted identified botanical specimens (Box 3)
- Letters from Adelaide Taber Young, at Cornell, to her mother, 1895-1900 (Box 4)